<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>References on ResNet Storymaps</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/references/</link>
    <description>Recent content in References on ResNet Storymaps</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/references/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/references/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/references/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Brittney &#xD;&#xA;1. Canadian Wildlife Services. (2023). Canadian National Wetlands Inventory [Nova Scotia and New Brunswick]. Environment and Climate Change Canada. https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;2. Heiri, O., Lotter, A. F., &amp; Lemcke, G. (2001). Loss on ignition as a method for estimating organic and carbonate content in sediments: Reproducibility and comparability of results. Journal of Paleolimnology, 25(1), 101–110. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008119611481&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;3. Maxwell, T. L., Rovai, A. S., Adame, M. F., Adams, J. B., Álvarez-Rogel, J., Austin, W. E. N., Beasy, K., Boscutti, F., Böttcher, M. E., Bouma, T. J., Bulmer, R. H., Burden, A., Burke, S. A., Camacho, S., Chaudhary, D. R., Chmura, G. L., Copertino, M., Cott, G. M., Craft, C., … Worthington, T. A. (2023). Global dataset of soil organic carbon in tidal marshes. Scientific Data, 10(1), 797. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-023-02633-x &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;4. Howard, J., Hoyt, S., Isensee, K., Pidgeon, E., Telszewski, M. (eds.) (2014). Coastal Blue Carbon: Methods for assessing carbon stocks and emissions factors in mangroves, tidal salt marshes, and seagrass meadows. Conservation International, Intergovernmental Oceanographic Commission of UNESCO, International Union for Conservation of Nature. Arlington, Virginia, USA. https://www.thebluecarboninitiative.org/manual&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;5. Burt DW and Wallis M. 1997. Assessment of salmonid habitat in the salmon river, salmon arm. Department of Fisheries and Oceans. Vancouver, B.C. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Gabriela&#xD;&#xA;6. Torchio, G. M.; Cimon-Morin, J.; Mendes, P.; Goyette, J-O.; Schwantes, A.M.; Arias-Patino, M.; Bennett, E.M.; Destrempes, C.; Pellerin, S.  and Poulin, M. From Marginal Croplands to Natural Habitats: A Framework for Assessing the Restoration Potential to Enhance Wild-Bee Pollination in Agricultural Landscapes. Submitted for publication.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Peter M&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;7. Venter, O., Sanderson, E.W., Magrach, A., Allan, J.R., Beher, J., Jones, K.R., Possingham, H.P., Laurance, W.F., Wood, P., Fekete, B.M., Levy, M.A., Watson, J.E.M., 2016. Sixteen years of change in the global terrestrial human footprint and implications for biodiversity conservation. Nature Communications 7, 12558.. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms12558&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;8. Sherren, K., K. Ellis, J. A. Guimond, B, Kurylyk, N. LeRoux, J. Lundholm, M. L. Mallory, D. van Proosdij, A. K. Walker, T. M. Bowron, J. Brazner, L. Kellman, B. L. Turner II, and E. Wells. Understanding multifunctional Bay of Fundy dykelands and tidal wetlands using ecosystem services—a baseline. FACETS. 6(): 1446-1473. https://doi.org/10.1139/facets-2020-0073&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;9. Hillis, Dylan &amp; Gustas, Robert &amp; Pauly, Daniel &amp; Cheung, William &amp; Salomon, Anne &amp; McKechnie, Iain. (2022). A palaeothermometer of ancient Indigenous fisheries reveals increases in mean temperature of the catch over five millennia. Environmental Biology of Fishes. 105. 10.1007/s10641-022-01243-7.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;10. Mendes, P., Bourgeois, B., Pellerin, S. et al. Linkages between plant functional diversity and soil-based ecosystem services in urban and peri-urban vacant lots. Urban Ecosyst (2024). https://doi.org/10.1007/s11252-023-01470-5&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;11. Krishna Bahadur KC, Arthur Gill Green, Dan Wassmansdorf, Vivek Gandhi, Khurram Nadeem, and Evan D.G. Fraser. Opportunities and trade-offs for expanding agriculture in Canada’s North: an ecosystem service perspective. FACETS. 6(): 1728-1752. https://doi.org/10.1139/facets-2020-0097&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;12. Lemay, Margaret &amp; Radcliffe, Josalyn &amp; Bysouth, David &amp; Spring, Andrew. (2021). Northern Food Systems in Transition: The Role of the Emerging Agri-Food Industry in the Northwest Territories (Canada) Food System. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 5. 661538. 10.3389/fsufs.2021.661538.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;13. Brown, G., and N. Fagerholm, 2015. Empirical PPGIS/PGIS mapping of ecosystem services: A review and evaluation, Ecosystem Services 13,119-133, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2014.10.007.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;14. Kumar, M.B., C. Furgal, P. Hutchinson, W. Roseborough and S. Kootoo‑Chiarello. 2019. Harvesting activities among First Nations people living off reserve, Métis and Inuit: Time trends, barriers and associated factors. Statistics Canada. Catalogue no. 89‑653‑X2019001.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;15. MacKinnon, A, and L. Kershaw. 2015. Edible and Medicinal Plants of Canada. Lone Pine Publishing, Vancouver.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;16. Turner, N.J. (ed.) 2020. Plants, Peoples, and Places: The Roles of Ethnobotany and Ethnoecology in Indigenous Peoples’ Land Rights in Canada and Beyond. McGill-Queen’s University Press, Montreal and Kingston.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;17. Lyon, C., Saupe, E.E., Smith, C.J., Hill, D.J., Beckerman, A.P., Stringer, L.C., Marchant, R., Mckay, J., Burke, A., O’Higgins, P., Dunhill, A.M., Allen, B.J., Riel‐Salvatore, J., Aze, T., 2022. Climate change research and action must look beyond 2100. Global Change Biology 28, 349–361.. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.15871&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Miguel&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Tourigny, E.D., 2020. Maintaining Traditions: Food and Identity among Early Immigrants to Upper Canada. Historical Archaeology 54, 354–374.. https://doi.org/10.1007/s41636-020-00237-5 &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;18. Oreskes, N., Shrader-Frechette, K., &amp; Belitz, K. (1994). Verification, validation, and confirmation of numerical models in the earth sciences. Science, 263(5147), 641–646. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.263.5147.641&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;19. Brimicombe, A. (2010). GIS, Environmental Modeling and Engineering. CRC Press.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;20. Williams, B. A., Venter, O., Allan, J. R., Atkinson, S. C., Rehbein, J. A., Ward, M., Di Marco, M., Grantham, H. S., Ervin, J., Goetz, S. J., Hansen, A. J., Jantz, P., Pillay, R., Rodríguez-Buriticá, S., Supples, C., Virnig, A. L. S., &amp; Watson, J. E. M. (2020). Change in Terrestrial Human Footprint Drives Continued Loss of Intact Ecosystems. One Earth, 3(3), 371–382. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.009&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;21. Hirsh-Pearson, K., Johnson, C. J., Schuster, R., Wheate, R. D., Venter, O., &amp; Hirsh, K. (2022). Canada’s human footprint reveals large intact areas juxtaposed against areas under immense anthropogenic pressure. Https://Doi.Org/10.1139/Facets-2021-0063, 7, 398–419. https://doi.org/10.1139/FACETS-2021-0063&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Woolmer, G., Trombulak, S. C., Ray, J. C., Doran, P. J., Anderson, M. G., Baldwin, R. F., Morgan, A., &amp;    Sanderson, E. W. (2008). Rescaling the Human Footprint: A tool for conservation planning at an ecoregional scale. Landscape and Urban Planning, 87(1), 42–53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2008.04.005 --&gt;  &#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canadian Wildlife Services. (2023). Canadian National Wetlands Inventory [Nova Scotia and New Brunswick]. Environment and Climate Change Canada, Government of Canada. &lt;a href=&#34;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&#34;&gt;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
