<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Spatial, temporal, and scale mismatches on ResNet Storymaps</title>
    <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Spatial, temporal, and scale mismatches on ResNet Storymaps</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spatial, temporal, and scale mismatches</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the need for an ecosystem service (demand) and the ability of the environment to provide that service (supply) don&amp;rsquo;t match up. No-overlap between supply and demand can occur either in different places (spatial mismatch), at different times (temporal mismatch) or at different scales (scale mismatch).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, some insects, small mammals, and birds contribute to fertilization of plants (that is, to pollination) while they are feeding and moving among flowers. Where pollinators originate from in the landscape is the area of pollination supply. On the other side, demand for pollination occurs where there are plants that need pollination. For pollination to occur, pollinators have to move from their nesting places to their feeding sites. When there is a large separation between where pollinators originate from (supply) and where they feed and pollinate (demand), supply and demand do not match in space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure w-100 p-3&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/fig1.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/fig1.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--- Make image larger, possibly lightbox ---&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll explore some examples of when demand and supply don&amp;rsquo;t line up using the ecosystem service of pollination as an example. This mismatch&#xA;can happen in three main ways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- #45.582, -73.315&#xA;&#xA;1) **Spatial mismatch**: If we look at different landscapes, even when there&#39;s the same amount of space for pollinators, some farmlands may have &#xA;more pollinators simply because their crops are closer to nesting sites. The location and the configuration of nesting sites can influence the &#xA;availability of pollinators inside fields. For example, studies in crop fields show that the abundance of pollinators tends to be higher in &#xA;smaller crop fields (e.g. 2 ha) than in large ones (e.g. 100 ha). If crop fields&#39; edges have suitable places for pollinators to nest, then &#xA;pollinators will find it easier to fly to the center of the field and pollinate smaller fields compared to larger fields. The plants in the &#xA;center of a large field might be out of reach for some pollinators, given their limited flying range.&#xA;&#xA;2) **Temporal mismatch**: Not all pollinators are active at the same time nor during all seasons of crop blooming. Crops may bloom at times that &#xA;do not always coincide with all insects’s periods of high activity. As the climate changes, the periods of time when crops bloom and the periods &#xA;of time when bees have high activity may no longer align, which may result in greater temporal mismatches.&#xA;&#xA;3) **Scale mismatch**: The entire process of pollination needs a specific size and arrangement of the land. One farmer might not have enough land to &#xA;establish a nice hedgerow or a flower strip to support the pollinators, or arrange it in the best way for them. But if many farmers work together, &#xA;they might be able to create the right conditions for pollinators. This means that encouraging cooperation between farmers might be more successful &#xA;than asking one farmer to increase bee-friendly habitats. This is because the size of a single farm might be too small to match the large-scale needs &#xA;of the pollination process, and this is an example of scale mismatch.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spatial mismatch&lt;/strong&gt;: Let&amp;rsquo;s think of bees, as an example of pollinators. Bees fly from their nests to flowering crops, which are a good source of pollen or nectar. In the process of feeding, bees pollinate crops by transporting pollen among flowers. In this example, bees can be regarded as the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; of pollination, whereas the crops that are pollinated represent the &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for pollination. Empirical studies in crop fields show that the abundance of pollinators tends to be higher in smaller crop fields (e.g., 2 ha) than in large ones (e.g., 100 ha). Why is that? One explanation is that if bees&amp;rsquo; nesting habitat is located relatively close to crop fields (including plants located in the center of the field), then they will find it easier to fly and pollinate all plants present in the field. In that case, there is a spatial match between the supply of pollination (bees) and the demand (crops). Now imagine a very large crop, where plants located in the middle of the field are far from bees&amp;rsquo; nesting habitat, so far that bees won&amp;rsquo;t fly there. In that case, there is a spatial mismatch between pollination supply and demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand the ecosystem service area&lt;/strong&gt;: Think about the whole area that benefits from the ecosystem service, like pollination, and identify who or what benefits from it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare across beneficiaries&lt;/strong&gt;: Look at different groups or areas that benefit from the service and compare them. This can help identify different needs and how&#xA;they might be met.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify the benefit gap&lt;/strong&gt;: Try to figure out where the mismatches between supply and demand are. Where are the needs not being met? Understanding this gap can&#xA;help in planning how to fix it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about the arrangement and size of habitat areas&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s not just about how much habitat there is for the pollinators, but also about how this&#xA;habitat is arranged. The layout and size of the land can influence how well it supports the pollinators and provides the needed service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By considering these points, we can better understand how to manage and support many ecosystem services like pollination. It helps in creating a plan that fits&#xA;the specific needs of the area and the people who depend on these services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Torchio, G. M.; Cimon-Morin, J.; Mendes, P.; Goyette, J-O.; Schwantes, A.M.; Arias-Patino, M.; Bennett, E.M.; Destrempes, C.; Pellerin, S.  and Poulin, M. From Marginal Croplands to Natural Habitats: A Framework for Assessing the Restoration Potential to Enhance Wild-Bee Pollination in Agricultural Landscapes. Submitted for publication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
