<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modelling at different scales on ResNet Storymaps</title>
    <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modelling at different scales on ResNet Storymaps</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Modelling at different scales</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure float-end w-50 d-block&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/unknownSourceAskM_v2.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Modelling at different spatial scales often involves trade-offs between model complexity, accuracy (and/or precision), generalization and spatial extent (or spatial resolution).&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/unknownSourceAskM_v2.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Modelling at different spatial scales often involves trade-offs between model complexity, accuracy (and/or precision), generalization and spatial extent (or spatial resolution).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decision-making and research questions are meaningful at specific scales and often need scale-specific models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Choosing the right size (extent) to study natural phenomena is hard for scientists (Oreskes et al., 1994 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;). The scale chosen will determine how much detail and how accurate the model is, and also, how much area the model can cover. The scale of a study significantly impacts the models complexity, their accuracy, spatial extent, and generalizability (figure on the right) (Brimicombe, 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;).&#xA;&#xA;Researching at a local scale or a small proportion of the territory requires more complex analyses. Researchers need to consider more variables and their relationships to achieve a reliable approximation of the natural phenomena under investigation. Also, the identification of patterns could be more difficult at smaller scales. Furthermore, obtaining more detailed results demands more computational resources. Nevertheless, higher scales at a finer resolution do not always lead to higher accuracy (Brimicombe, 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;).&#xA;&#xA;On the other hand, examining natural phenomena at larger scales, such as regional or global studies, may enhance comprehension of the phenomena. Coarser resolutions lead to reduced complexity, simplifying models’ inputs and outputs. Also, some relationships or patterns emerge to significant geographical extents. Furthermore, policymakers tend to favor regional and global scales, as they provide a broader perspective on reality.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Selecting the appropriate extent and resolution to study natural phenomena poses a significant challenge for scientists (Oreskes et al., 1994 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;). The chosen extent dictates the area the model can encompass, while the selected spatial resolution determines the level of detail and accuracy the model achieves. Hence, the spatial extent and resolution of a study significantly affects model complexity, accuracy (and/or precision), and generalizability (figure on the right) (Brimicombe, 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study: Human pressures at different scales</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The human footprint is a cumulative index that quantifies the extent and the intensity of human pressures on ecosystems and biodiversity. We compared the Human footprint at three scales: global (Williams et al., 2020 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt;), national (Hirsh-Pearson et al., 2022 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt;), and provincial &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--The map on the right represents the state of human pressures in the northeast of British Columbia. From coarse (global) to detailed (provincial) scales, we can easily identify how roads are represented to different extents. The global model captures a broad perspective of human disturbances, in which roads and settlements are the most visible features. This global map is improved with the national model, which integrates 12 layers of information, providing the appearance of more levels of detail such as oil and gas infrastructure and mining. The provincial map, which incorporates 16 layers of information, shows a more comprehensive state of the human footprint, including seismic lines, oil and gas wells, and infrastructure, and even recreational features.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interactive maps on the right represent the state of human pressures in the northeast of British Columbia. From coarse (Global Human Footprint) to detailed (Provincial Human Footprint) spatial resolution (scales), we can easily identify how roads are represented at different extents. The global model captures a broad perspective of human disturbances in which roads and settlements are the most visible features. The resolution of this global map is improved with the national model (National Human Footprint), which integrates 12 layers of information, providing more levels of detail such as oil and gas infrastructure and mining. The provincial map (Provincial Human Footprint), which incorporates 16 layers of information, shows a more comprehensive state of the human footprint, including seismic lines, oil and gas wells, human infrastructure, and even recreational features. By &lt;em&gt;turning on and off the different spatial layers&lt;/em&gt; on the right, differences in spatial resolution can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Models are very sensitive to the input data, so the more accurate the input data, the higher the reliability of the model. On the other hand, models are developed to be applied at a certain scale (spatial and temporal), and most times they are not useful to be directly applied at other scales. A model acceptable at one scale might not be at another. Another important consideration is that model evaluation can be a complex process itself. So, the larger the spatial and temporal scale of the phenomena, the evaluation of the model is more complex and challenging.&#xA;&#xA;Regarding these aspects, we suggest the following to improve reliability of model:&#xA;&#xA;1. Be clear about the purpose of the model and verify that it applies to the scale considered.  &#xA;2. Document all decisions made regarding the input data (sources, decisions made to incorporate it, etc.).  &#xA;3. Create clear and explicit criteria for every step of the model evaluation. Always document what you did and why  &#xA;4. Conduct a sensitivity analysis to test the consistency of the model under a range of input parameters.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Models are very sensitive to input data, so the more accurate the input data, the higher the reliability of the model. On the other hand, models are developed to be applied at a certain scale (spatial and temporal), and most times they should not be directly applied at other scales. A model that is acceptable at one scale might not be at another. Another important consideration is that model evaluation can be a complex process in itself. Hence, the larger the spatial and temporal scale of the phenomena being studied the more complex and challenging the evaluation of the model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/refs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brimicombe, A. (2010). GIS, Environmental Modeling and Engineering. CRC Press.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hirsh-Pearson, K., Johnson, C. J., Schuster, R., Wheate, R. D., Venter, O., &amp;amp; Hirsh, K. (2022). Canada’s human footprint reveals large intact areas juxtaposed against areas under immense anthropogenic pressure. Https://Doi.Org/10.1139/Facets-2021-0063, 7, 398–419. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1139/FACETS-2021-0063&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1139/FACETS-2021-0063&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oreskes, N., Shrader-Frechette, K., &amp;amp; Belitz, K. (1994). Verification, validation, and confirmation of numerical models in the earth sciences. Science, 263(5147), 641–646. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.263.5147.641&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.263.5147.641&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Williams, B. A., Venter, O., Allan, J. R., Atkinson, S. C., Rehbein, J. A., Ward, M., Di Marco, M., Grantham, H. S., Ervin, J., Goetz, S. J., Hansen, A. J., Jantz, P., Pillay, R., Rodríguez-Buriticá, S., Supples, C.,&#xA;Virnig, A. L. S., &amp;amp; Watson, J. E. M. (2020). Change in Terrestrial Human Footprint Drives Continued Loss of Intact Ecosystems. One Earth, 3(3), 371–382. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
