<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Importance of field sampling on ResNet Storymaps</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Importance of field sampling on ResNet Storymaps</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The importance of field sampling and data collection for scaling of ecosystem services</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/challenge1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/challenge1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Scaling requires data. For many ecosystem services, data is collected through field sampling. Many challenges exist when conducting field work to collect data, including:&#xA;&#xA;- The trade-off between the number of data points needed and the time and resources available to collect, process, and analyze field samples.&#xA;&#xA;- Thorough background research is needed to choose a proper sampling scheme for the ecological questions being explored.&#xA;&#xA;- Data collected for one study’s questions may not be applicable to a study that aims to scale ecosystem services up (or down).&#xA;&#xA;- Methodologies used to collect field data may not be the same between similar studies exploring the same ecosystem service.&#xA;&#xA;- Unexpected situations often occur while conducting field or lab work (e.g. equipment breaking or weather events) and often information can be missing from datasets.&#xA;&#xA;- The heterogeneity of the environment does not guarantee that data points collected reflect the true spatial and temporal variability that exists in the ecosystem being studied.&#xA;&#xA;This section will describe the challenges and best practices of collecting soil carbon data from two different ecosystems \- salt marshes along the Bay of Fundy and forests and agricultural land in the Northwest Territories.”--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When studying ecosystems, scientists often collect data in the field. For example, soil samples can be taken in the field to estimate how much carbon there is in a particular location. Often, we use local field data together with models to understand what may be happening over a larger area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ### Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1--choosing-representative-sites-and-study-areas&#34;&gt;Step 1:  Choosing representative sites and study areas&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Four study sites in the Upper Bay of Fundy along the Cumberland Basin were chosen to represent salt marshes at different stages of restoration:  Converse - newly restored, Aulac - restored over 10 years ago, John Lusby - passively restored over 50 years ago, and Wood Point Rest Stop - natural reference site. Sites were chosen to be close to one another (&lt;10 km apart) so environmental conditions like tides and weather were similar between sites. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four sites were chosen in this study to represent salt marshes at different stages of restoration: Converse - newly restored, Aulac - restored over 10 years ago, John Lusby - passively restored over 70 years ago, and Wood Point Rest Stop - natural reference site. Sites were located close to one another (&amp;lt;10 km apart) so environmental conditions like tides and weather were similar between sites. The basemap shows the extent of tidal marsh in the Upper Bay of Fundy along the Cumberland Basin based on geospatial data available in the Canadian National Wetlands Inventory &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each site was divided into three elevation zones that are flooded by tides differently throughout the year: the low zone is flooded by ~75% of high tides in a year, the mid zone is flooded by ~50% of high tides, and the high zone is flooded by ~25% of high tides. These zones were based on flooding frequency because decomposition of organic matter by microbes is slowed down in flooded, low-oxygen conditions. The layers displayed on the basemap for the Wood Point Rest Stop site were created by simulating different tidal flooding heights over a publicly available Digital Elevation Model (DEM) for New Brunswick &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-2--collection-of-sediment-cores&#34;&gt;Step 2:  Collection of sediment cores&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &lt;div class=&#34;images-container&#34;&gt; &#xA;![fig3](images/survey.jpg &#34; &#34;) &#xA;{width=&#34;50%&#34;}&#xA;&#xA;![fig4](images/image40.png &#34; &#34;)&#xA;{width=&#34;40%&#34;}&#xA;&#xA;![fig5](images/image17.png &#34; &#34;) &#xA;{width=&#34;40%&#34;} &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Three random points within each zone were chosen for core extraction using Geographic Information System (GIS) software (ArcGIS Pro) and the location of each point was surveyed using a high-accuracy GPS system. In total, nine cores were collected from each study site. The photo below (left) shows someone surveying core locations at the Aulac site. The maps below show the location of nine cores in the Wood Point Rest Stop study site within the three elevation zones. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within a designated study area of each site, three random points within each zone were chosen for core extraction using Geographic Information System (GIS) software (ArcGIS Pro) and the location of each point was surveyed using a high-accuracy GPS system. In total, nine cores were collected from each study site. The basemap shows where the nine cores were collected in the Wood Point Rest Stop study site within the three elevation zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-3--processing-of-cores-in-the-lab&#34;&gt;Step 3:  Processing of cores in the lab&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once back in the lab, processing the core starts. The cores are photographed and different features like soil colour and texture are described and recorded. Then cores are divided into different increments depending on the goals of the study. For this study, 5 cm increments were chosen for a total of 10 per 50 cm core, which means that 360 individual samples were processed! When dividing cores, a compression factor should be used to adjust the increment length based on the compaction measured in the field. Compaction is often assumed equal across the entirety of the core, unless compaction is measured periodically throughout the core extraction process in the field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-4--lab-analyses-for-bulk-density-and-loss-on-ignition-loi&#34;&gt;Step 4:  Lab analyses for bulk density and loss-on-ignition (LOI)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--The soil samples of known volume taken from the core are first dried to determine the bulk density. Wet samples are placed in individually labeled tins, weighed, and then dried at 60 ℃ in a drying oven for 24-72 hours (or until a consistent dried weight is reached). After they are completely dry, they are re-weighed to determine dry weight of the soil sample. The photos below show the dried soil cylinders in a dessicator after the oven, which ensures the samples are fully dried before being re-weighed. Bulk density is written as the dry weight of soil divided by the known volume of the sample (grams per cm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Low bulk density means there is not a lot of soil within the volume of core sampled, which means the soil is less densely packed and there are more air pockets. Soils with low bulk density often have high organic matter content and water-holding capacity (like a sponge!). --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wet samples are placed in individually labeled tins, weighed, and then dried at 60 ℃ in a drying oven for 24-72 hours (or until a consistent dried weight is reached). After they are completely dry, they are re-weighed to determine dry weight of the soil sample. The images below show the dried soil cylinders in a desiccator, which allows the samples to cool down to room temperature without absorbing any moisture before being re-weighed. Bulk density is written as the dry weight of soil divided by the known volume of the sample (grams per cm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Low bulk density means there is not a lot of soil within the volume of core sampled, which means the soil is less densely packed and there are more air pockets. Soils with low bulk density often have high organic matter content and water-holding capacity (like a sponge!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-5--data-processing-and-interpretation&#34;&gt;Step 5:  Data processing and interpretation&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Once bulk density and % organic matter are determined, the ‘organic carbon density’ of each increment of the core can be estimated. Often % organic matter (%OM) is converted to % organic carbon (%OC) in salt marshes using a known conversion equation published in the scientific literature or roughly estimated by simply dividing %OM by 2. Some studies choose to determine the exact amount of organic carbon (%OC) in their samples by conducting ‘elemental analysis’ or sending the samples to another lab to do this analysis. More and more studies are now sending at least a subset of samples away to determine their own %OM-to-%OC conversion equations. Either way, this step involves more time to process samples or more money to pay for the analysis. In addition, soil samples should be treated to remove any inorganic carbon so elemental analysis results only reflect total organic carbon. The figure below is pulled directly from Craft et al. 1991 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; and shows the relationship between %OM and %OC for brackish and salt marsh sediments in North Carolina. For the data presented below in this case study, a local equation for %OM-to%OC was developed using data from sites located in the Upper Bay of Fundy. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once bulk density and % organic matter are determined, the ‘organic carbon density’ of each increment of the core can be estimated. Often % organic matter (%OM) is converted to % organic carbon (%OC) in salt marshes using a known conversion equation published in the scientific literature. Some studies choose to determine the exact amount of organic carbon (%OC) in their samples by conducting ‘elemental analysis’ and creating their own %OM-to-%OC conversion equation for their specific region. This step involves more time to process samples or more money to pay for the analysis. In addition, soil samples should be acidified to remove any inorganic carbon present so elemental analysis results only reflect total organic carbon. Maxwell et al. (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; have recently published the most comprehensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-023-02633-x/figures/4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conversion equation&lt;/a&gt; for soil organic matter (SOM) to soil organic carbon (SOC) in tidal marshes to date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/acknowledgements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/acknowledgements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with any field work campaign, many hands went into collecting and processing this field data. Thank you to Elisha Richardson for providing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.behance.net/gallery/146604233/Tidal-Inundation-ArcPy-Model&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ArcPy script&lt;/a&gt; that was used to create the shapefile layers for the three flooding zones. Thank you to Emily Head, Stephanie MacIntyre, and Leila Rashid for help collecting cores in the field. Also thank you to L. Rashid for help processing bulk density and LOI samples in the lab.  Further thanks to Dr. Gail Chmura for sharing accommodations with us and Dr. Jeff Ollerhead for use of his gouge auger. Many methods used in this case study to collect and process cores were based on guidance in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebluecarboninitiative.org/manual&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blue Carbon Manual&lt;/a&gt; by Howard et al. (2014) &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 2: Soil carbon trade-offs associated with agricultural land use change in the Northwest Territories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ### Case Study 2: Soil carbon trade-offs associated with agricultural land use change in the Northwest Territories --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1-choosing-representative-sites-and-study-areas&#34;&gt;Step 1: Choosing representative sites and study areas&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We partnered with communities in the Northwest Territories, Canada such as Kakisa (shown here) to understand carbon and fertility trade-offs associated with agricultural cultivation of the boreal forest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure mx-auto d-block&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/image23.jpg&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Image by David Bysouth.&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/image23.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Image by David Bysouth.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2019, a soil sampling effort was conducted to assess the soil fertility and carbon content of sites that communities were interested in for agricultural development. Study sites were selected across a gradient of potential agriculture suitability ranging from class 3 (potentially the most suitable for agriculture) to class 7 (likely unsuitable for agriculture). Sites were also selected based on input from local community members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices and Opportunities</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best Practices and Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Collecting field data for scaling requires:&#xA;1. Funding and resources. &#xA;2. Background research to plan the most effective sampling scheme to capture as much variability as possible. &#xA;3. A network of researchers, stakeholders, and community members using standard methodologies to allow for the comparison of data across time and space. &#xA;4. Collaboration with people using the data (e.g. modelers) to help identify the type of data that will be needed before it is collected. &#xA;&#xA;Spending the time planning your field work is essential. Integration of modelers in this planning is even more important if the data is intended to be used in future studies of scaling. Planning ensures unexpected events and missing data can be dealt with and will not influence the overall dataset. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Field data challenges and opportunities --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Field sampling is important for assessing many ecosystem services. However, it is important to have the following points in mind before engaging in field data collection:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA; &lt;!--Craft, C. B., Seneca, E. D., &amp; Broome, S. W. (1991). Loss on Ignition and Kjeldahl Digestion for Estimating Organic Carbon and Total Nitrogen in Estuarine Marsh Soils: Calibration with Dry Combustion. Estuaries, 14(2), 175. https://doi.org/10.2307/1351691 --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canadian Wildlife Services. (2023). Canadian National Wetlands Inventory [Nova Scotia and New Brunswick]. Environment and Climate Change Canada. &lt;a href=&#34;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&#34;&gt;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heiri, O., Lotter, A. F., &amp;amp; Lemcke, G. (2001). Loss on ignition as a method for estimating organic and carbonate content in sediments: Reproducibility and comparability of results. Journal of Paleolimnology, 25(1), 101–110. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008119611481&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008119611481&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
