<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ResNet Storymaps</title>
    <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/</link>
    <description>Recent content on ResNet Storymaps</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Glossary</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/glossary/glossary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/glossary/glossary/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;glossary&#34;&gt;Glossary&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;did-you-find-some-difficult-to-understand-jargon-in-this-story-map&#34;&gt;Did you find some difficult-to-understand jargon in this story map?&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s likely that you did, and for that reason we made this glossary of some fancy scientific terms, to help you navigate this story map.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;re not diving too deep on definitions, just giving you the basics to keep things clear! Words can have different meanings in different contexts, and we, scientists, are picky about it. So, we&amp;rsquo;re sticking to the meanings that matter for our story map.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/1_introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/1_introduction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scientists often work at different scales to analyze different parts of a landscape or ecosystem. We can study ecosystems at different scales across &lt;strong&gt;space&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e., spatial scale) or across &lt;strong&gt;time&lt;/strong&gt; (i.e., temporal scale). We can also ask “&lt;strong&gt;how big?&lt;/strong&gt;” (i.e., what is the extent?) or “&lt;strong&gt;how much detail?&lt;/strong&gt;” (i.e., what is the resolution?).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making good predictions</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2c/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2c/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We often assume that a relationship between two variables is linear; however, if we increase or reduce the spatial extent of a study, we may see a nonlinear relationship appear. This matters because we often use data from one area to make predictions for other areas. If we assume the relationship is linear when it’s not, our predictions will be wrong.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Modelling at different scales</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure float-end w-50 d-block&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/unknownSourceAskM_v2.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Modelling at different spatial scales often involves trade-offs between model complexity, accuracy (and/or precision), generalization and spatial extent (or spatial resolution).&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/unknownSourceAskM_v2.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Modelling at different spatial scales often involves trade-offs between model complexity, accuracy (and/or precision), generalization and spatial extent (or spatial resolution).&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Decision-making and research questions are meaningful at specific scales and often need scale-specific models.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Choosing the right size (extent) to study natural phenomena is hard for scientists (Oreskes et al., 1994 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;). The scale chosen will determine how much detail and how accurate the model is, and also, how much area the model can cover. The scale of a study significantly impacts the models complexity, their accuracy, spatial extent, and generalizability (figure on the right) (Brimicombe, 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;).&#xA;&#xA;Researching at a local scale or a small proportion of the territory requires more complex analyses. Researchers need to consider more variables and their relationships to achieve a reliable approximation of the natural phenomena under investigation. Also, the identification of patterns could be more difficult at smaller scales. Furthermore, obtaining more detailed results demands more computational resources. Nevertheless, higher scales at a finer resolution do not always lead to higher accuracy (Brimicombe, 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;).&#xA;&#xA;On the other hand, examining natural phenomena at larger scales, such as regional or global studies, may enhance comprehension of the phenomena. Coarser resolutions lead to reduced complexity, simplifying models’ inputs and outputs. Also, some relationships or patterns emerge to significant geographical extents. Furthermore, policymakers tend to favor regional and global scales, as they provide a broader perspective on reality.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Selecting the appropriate extent and resolution to study natural phenomena poses a significant challenge for scientists (Oreskes et al., 1994 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[18]&lt;/a&gt;). The chosen extent dictates the area the model can encompass, while the selected spatial resolution determines the level of detail and accuracy the model achieves. Hence, the spatial extent and resolution of a study significantly affects model complexity, accuracy (and/or precision), and generalizability (figure on the right) (Brimicombe, 2010 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[19]&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/references/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/references/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Brittney &#xD;&#xA;1. Canadian Wildlife Services. (2023). Canadian National Wetlands Inventory [Nova Scotia and New Brunswick]. Environment and Climate Change Canada. https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;2. Heiri, O., Lotter, A. F., &amp; Lemcke, G. (2001). Loss on ignition as a method for estimating organic and carbonate content in sediments: Reproducibility and comparability of results. Journal of Paleolimnology, 25(1), 101–110. https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008119611481&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;3. Maxwell, T. L., Rovai, A. S., Adame, M. F., Adams, J. B., Álvarez-Rogel, J., Austin, W. E. N., Beasy, K., Boscutti, F., Böttcher, M. E., Bouma, T. J., Bulmer, R. H., Burden, A., Burke, S. A., Camacho, S., Chaudhary, D. R., Chmura, G. L., Copertino, M., Cott, G. M., Craft, C., … Worthington, T. A. (2023). Global dataset of soil organic carbon in tidal marshes. Scientific Data, 10(1), 797. https://doi.org/10.1038/s41597-023-02633-x &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;4. Howard, J., Hoyt, S., Isensee, K., Pidgeon, E., Telszewski, M. (eds.) (2014). Coastal Blue Carbon: Methods for assessing carbon stocks and emissions factors in mangroves, tidal salt marshes, and seagrass meadows. Conservation International, Intergovernmental Oceanographic Commission of UNESCO, International Union for Conservation of Nature. Arlington, Virginia, USA. https://www.thebluecarboninitiative.org/manual&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;5. Burt DW and Wallis M. 1997. Assessment of salmonid habitat in the salmon river, salmon arm. Department of Fisheries and Oceans. Vancouver, B.C. &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Gabriela&#xD;&#xA;6. Torchio, G. M.; Cimon-Morin, J.; Mendes, P.; Goyette, J-O.; Schwantes, A.M.; Arias-Patino, M.; Bennett, E.M.; Destrempes, C.; Pellerin, S.  and Poulin, M. From Marginal Croplands to Natural Habitats: A Framework for Assessing the Restoration Potential to Enhance Wild-Bee Pollination in Agricultural Landscapes. Submitted for publication.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Peter M&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;7. Venter, O., Sanderson, E.W., Magrach, A., Allan, J.R., Beher, J., Jones, K.R., Possingham, H.P., Laurance, W.F., Wood, P., Fekete, B.M., Levy, M.A., Watson, J.E.M., 2016. Sixteen years of change in the global terrestrial human footprint and implications for biodiversity conservation. Nature Communications 7, 12558.. https://doi.org/10.1038/ncomms12558&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;8. Sherren, K., K. Ellis, J. A. Guimond, B, Kurylyk, N. LeRoux, J. Lundholm, M. L. Mallory, D. van Proosdij, A. K. Walker, T. M. Bowron, J. Brazner, L. Kellman, B. L. Turner II, and E. Wells. Understanding multifunctional Bay of Fundy dykelands and tidal wetlands using ecosystem services—a baseline. FACETS. 6(): 1446-1473. https://doi.org/10.1139/facets-2020-0073&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;9. Hillis, Dylan &amp; Gustas, Robert &amp; Pauly, Daniel &amp; Cheung, William &amp; Salomon, Anne &amp; McKechnie, Iain. (2022). A palaeothermometer of ancient Indigenous fisheries reveals increases in mean temperature of the catch over five millennia. Environmental Biology of Fishes. 105. 10.1007/s10641-022-01243-7.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;10. Mendes, P., Bourgeois, B., Pellerin, S. et al. Linkages between plant functional diversity and soil-based ecosystem services in urban and peri-urban vacant lots. Urban Ecosyst (2024). https://doi.org/10.1007/s11252-023-01470-5&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;11. Krishna Bahadur KC, Arthur Gill Green, Dan Wassmansdorf, Vivek Gandhi, Khurram Nadeem, and Evan D.G. Fraser. Opportunities and trade-offs for expanding agriculture in Canada’s North: an ecosystem service perspective. FACETS. 6(): 1728-1752. https://doi.org/10.1139/facets-2020-0097&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;12. Lemay, Margaret &amp; Radcliffe, Josalyn &amp; Bysouth, David &amp; Spring, Andrew. (2021). Northern Food Systems in Transition: The Role of the Emerging Agri-Food Industry in the Northwest Territories (Canada) Food System. Frontiers in Sustainable Food Systems. 5. 661538. 10.3389/fsufs.2021.661538.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;13. Brown, G., and N. Fagerholm, 2015. Empirical PPGIS/PGIS mapping of ecosystem services: A review and evaluation, Ecosystem Services 13,119-133, https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2014.10.007.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;14. Kumar, M.B., C. Furgal, P. Hutchinson, W. Roseborough and S. Kootoo‑Chiarello. 2019. Harvesting activities among First Nations people living off reserve, Métis and Inuit: Time trends, barriers and associated factors. Statistics Canada. Catalogue no. 89‑653‑X2019001.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;15. MacKinnon, A, and L. Kershaw. 2015. Edible and Medicinal Plants of Canada. Lone Pine Publishing, Vancouver.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;16. Turner, N.J. (ed.) 2020. Plants, Peoples, and Places: The Roles of Ethnobotany and Ethnoecology in Indigenous Peoples’ Land Rights in Canada and Beyond. McGill-Queen’s University Press, Montreal and Kingston.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;17. Lyon, C., Saupe, E.E., Smith, C.J., Hill, D.J., Beckerman, A.P., Stringer, L.C., Marchant, R., Mckay, J., Burke, A., O’Higgins, P., Dunhill, A.M., Allen, B.J., Riel‐Salvatore, J., Aze, T., 2022. Climate change research and action must look beyond 2100. Global Change Biology 28, 349–361.. https://doi.org/10.1111/gcb.15871&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Miguel&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Tourigny, E.D., 2020. Maintaining Traditions: Food and Identity among Early Immigrants to Upper Canada. Historical Archaeology 54, 354–374.. https://doi.org/10.1007/s41636-020-00237-5 &#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;18. Oreskes, N., Shrader-Frechette, K., &amp; Belitz, K. (1994). Verification, validation, and confirmation of numerical models in the earth sciences. Science, 263(5147), 641–646. https://doi.org/10.1126/science.263.5147.641&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;19. Brimicombe, A. (2010). GIS, Environmental Modeling and Engineering. CRC Press.&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;20. Williams, B. A., Venter, O., Allan, J. R., Atkinson, S. C., Rehbein, J. A., Ward, M., Di Marco, M., Grantham, H. S., Ervin, J., Goetz, S. J., Hansen, A. J., Jantz, P., Pillay, R., Rodríguez-Buriticá, S., Supples, C., Virnig, A. L. S., &amp; Watson, J. E. M. (2020). Change in Terrestrial Human Footprint Drives Continued Loss of Intact Ecosystems. One Earth, 3(3), 371–382. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.009&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;21. Hirsh-Pearson, K., Johnson, C. J., Schuster, R., Wheate, R. D., Venter, O., &amp; Hirsh, K. (2022). Canada’s human footprint reveals large intact areas juxtaposed against areas under immense anthropogenic pressure. Https://Doi.Org/10.1139/Facets-2021-0063, 7, 398–419. https://doi.org/10.1139/FACETS-2021-0063&#xD;&#xA;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;!-- Woolmer, G., Trombulak, S. C., Ray, J. C., Doran, P. J., Anderson, M. G., Baldwin, R. F., Morgan, A., &amp;    Sanderson, E. W. (2008). Rescaling the Human Footprint: A tool for conservation planning at an ecoregional scale. Landscape and Urban Planning, 87(1), 42–53. https://doi.org/10.1016/j.landurbplan.2008.04.005 --&gt;  &#xD;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canadian Wildlife Services. (2023). Canadian National Wetlands Inventory [Nova Scotia and New Brunswick]. Environment and Climate Change Canada, Government of Canada. &lt;a href=&#34;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&#34;&gt;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial resolution matters</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2a/1_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2a/1_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We often need detailed data to detect change. In this example, we discuss why we need data at finer pixel sizes to detect forest losses and gains.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we change the spatial resolution of a pixel, we change the number and type of elements (for example land cover types) that compose it. This can impact the results of our studies, especially those where we attempt to classify pixels based on their composition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial, temporal, and scale mismatches</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, the need for an ecosystem service (demand) and the ability of the environment to provide that service (supply) don&amp;rsquo;t match up. No-overlap between supply and demand can occur either in different places (spatial mismatch), at different times (temporal mismatch) or at different scales (scale mismatch).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For example, some insects, small mammals, and birds contribute to fertilization of plants (that is, to pollination) while they are feeding and moving among flowers. Where pollinators originate from in the landscape is the area of pollination supply. On the other side, demand for pollination occurs where there are plants that need pollination. For pollination to occur, pollinators have to move from their nesting places to their feeding sites. When there is a large separation between where pollinators originate from (supply) and where they feed and pollinate (demand), supply and demand do not match in space.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The choice of scale for summarizing data</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2b/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2b/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- We often report data by summarizing individual information (e.g., at a pixel) to coarser scale analysis units (e.g., census division). In this example, we discuss the consequences of summarizing data to different units.&#xA;&#xA;In addition to the resolution, boundaries used to aggregate smaller scale data may influence the visual assessment of ecosystem service supply and demand information and relationships. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We often report data by summarizing fine-scale information (e.g., at a pixel) to coarse-scale analysis or reporting units (e.g., census division). In this example, we discuss this challenge known as Modifiable Areal Unit Problem (MAUP) and how it may visually bias our understanding of ecosystem service supply and demand relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The future is not like the past</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- background should be the Monteregie region--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When researchers study ecosystem services they are often interested in how land uses have changed in the past and how they might change in the future, and as a result how the services provided shift in location and amount. More generally, just as researchers choose the spatial extent and grain for their studies, they also choose the temporal extent and grain, asking questions such as: How far back in time should I go? Do I only care about annual changes, or do I want to know about changes within years?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The importance of field sampling and data collection for scaling of ecosystem services</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/challenge1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/challenge1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Scaling requires data. For many ecosystem services, data is collected through field sampling. Many challenges exist when conducting field work to collect data, including:&#xA;&#xA;- The trade-off between the number of data points needed and the time and resources available to collect, process, and analyze field samples.&#xA;&#xA;- Thorough background research is needed to choose a proper sampling scheme for the ecological questions being explored.&#xA;&#xA;- Data collected for one study’s questions may not be applicable to a study that aims to scale ecosystem services up (or down).&#xA;&#xA;- Methodologies used to collect field data may not be the same between similar studies exploring the same ecosystem service.&#xA;&#xA;- Unexpected situations often occur while conducting field or lab work (e.g. equipment breaking or weather events) and often information can be missing from datasets.&#xA;&#xA;- The heterogeneity of the environment does not guarantee that data points collected reflect the true spatial and temporal variability that exists in the ecosystem being studied.&#xA;&#xA;This section will describe the challenges and best practices of collecting soil carbon data from two different ecosystems \- salt marshes along the Bay of Fundy and forests and agricultural land in the Northwest Territories.”--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When studying ecosystems, scientists often collect data in the field. For example, soil samples can be taken in the field to estimate how much carbon there is in a particular location. Often, we use local field data together with models to understand what may be happening over a larger area.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Time period matters</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To understand whether an ecosystem is changing, we measure it over time. However, if we only measure the ecosystem over a short time, then we may not detect a change, even when the ecosystem has changed. This example explores how the monitoring time-period influences outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often we use time series analysis to understand whether an ecosystem property or service is changing over time. The temporal extent (e.g., time frame or period) of the monitoring data can affect outcomes. For shorter time-series or time-series with high variability, we may not have a correct historical baseline to detect change. For example, if monitoring data does not extend far enough into the past, then an insignificant trend could be interpreted as evidence for stability or no effect, when in reality the system might already be in a degraded state.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2b/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2b/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Pollination supply and demand aggregated to watersheds (left) tend to show ecosystem service surplus (i.e. higher ratios) at areas with little demand, while the supply and demand relationships represented at 3km grid cells (right) can help identify more precisely high demand areas that could benefit from more agricultural support. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Pollination is beneficial to the production of certain crops such as soybean and fruit trees. Landscape areas with more nesting and floral resources are pollinator-suitable habitats. Pollinators such as bumble bees can fly from their habitats to nearby (~1.5km) crop fields and provide pollination service &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[23]&lt;/a&gt;. We summarize pollinator abundance index estimated using InVEST model, and pollination demand estimated based on the area of pollinator-dependent crops into 3km cells that can better capture effective pollination. We also summarize the information into the watersheds, which is a common scale for governance activities, to compare supply-demand relationships.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2c/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2c/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this case study, we explore the relationship between soil carbon and plant cover in vacant lots in Quebec City. The vacant lots were carefully chosen to cover the full range of plant cover. However, if a scientist only picked a few of these lots (like the green dots on the two left-hand figures), they might mistakenly think the relationship between soil carbon and plant cover is linear (as shown by the green line). This could lead to incorrect predictions for the entire area because when we look at data from the whole study region (shown on the right), we see the relationship is actually non-linear (the gray line). This nonlinear relationship could happen because in areas with high plant cover, other factors, like soil type or land use history, may play a role in explaining the carbon levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this example, we show how Chinook salmon populations are changing in the Salmon River, British Columbia, Canada. In this region, Chinook salmon are important for the way of life for Indigenous communities, the economy, and the environment. Here, we show differences in trend significance depending on the start of a monitoring program. For example, if salmon monitoring only started 10 or 20 years ago (click on “since 2010” or “since 2000” buttons), then no significant downward trend would have been detected. However, if we begin our time-series analysis in 1984, then we see a significant downward trend: slope = -0.046 and p-value &amp;lt; 0.001.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure w-100 p-3&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/fig1.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/fig1.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--- Make image larger, possibly lightbox ---&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll explore some examples of when demand and supply don&amp;rsquo;t line up using the ecosystem service of pollination as an example. This mismatch&#xA;can happen in three main ways:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- #45.582, -73.315&#xA;&#xA;1) **Spatial mismatch**: If we look at different landscapes, even when there&#39;s the same amount of space for pollinators, some farmlands may have &#xA;more pollinators simply because their crops are closer to nesting sites. The location and the configuration of nesting sites can influence the &#xA;availability of pollinators inside fields. For example, studies in crop fields show that the abundance of pollinators tends to be higher in &#xA;smaller crop fields (e.g. 2 ha) than in large ones (e.g. 100 ha). If crop fields&#39; edges have suitable places for pollinators to nest, then &#xA;pollinators will find it easier to fly to the center of the field and pollinate smaller fields compared to larger fields. The plants in the &#xA;center of a large field might be out of reach for some pollinators, given their limited flying range.&#xA;&#xA;2) **Temporal mismatch**: Not all pollinators are active at the same time nor during all seasons of crop blooming. Crops may bloom at times that &#xA;do not always coincide with all insects’s periods of high activity. As the climate changes, the periods of time when crops bloom and the periods &#xA;of time when bees have high activity may no longer align, which may result in greater temporal mismatches.&#xA;&#xA;3) **Scale mismatch**: The entire process of pollination needs a specific size and arrangement of the land. One farmer might not have enough land to &#xA;establish a nice hedgerow or a flower strip to support the pollinators, or arrange it in the best way for them. But if many farmers work together, &#xA;they might be able to create the right conditions for pollinators. This means that encouraging cooperation between farmers might be more successful &#xA;than asking one farmer to increase bee-friendly habitats. This is because the size of a single farm might be too small to match the large-scale needs &#xA;of the pollination process, and this is an example of scale mismatch.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spatial mismatch&lt;/strong&gt;: Let&amp;rsquo;s think of bees, as an example of pollinators. Bees fly from their nests to flowering crops, which are a good source of pollen or nectar. In the process of feeding, bees pollinate crops by transporting pollen among flowers. In this example, bees can be regarded as the &amp;ldquo;supply&amp;rdquo; of pollination, whereas the crops that are pollinated represent the &amp;ldquo;demand&amp;rdquo; for pollination. Empirical studies in crop fields show that the abundance of pollinators tends to be higher in smaller crop fields (e.g., 2 ha) than in large ones (e.g., 100 ha). Why is that? One explanation is that if bees&amp;rsquo; nesting habitat is located relatively close to crop fields (including plants located in the center of the field), then they will find it easier to fly and pollinate all plants present in the field. In that case, there is a spatial match between the supply of pollination (bees) and the demand (crops). Now imagine a very large crop, where plants located in the middle of the field are far from bees&amp;rsquo; nesting habitat, so far that bees won&amp;rsquo;t fly there. In that case, there is a spatial mismatch between pollination supply and demand.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The following case study illustrates some of the challenges with scaling up in time, and the differences between scaling up information from the past and predictions for the future.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;People obtain ecosystem services when they harvest wild plants (such as berries or mushrooms) from forested land. Such harvests go back hundreds of years in Canada, first by Indigenous peoples, then by settlers and now by a mix of different users (Kumar et al., 2019 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[14]&lt;/a&gt;; MacKinnon et al., 2015 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[15]&lt;/a&gt;; Turner, 2020 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[16]&lt;/a&gt;). With the adoption and spread of industrial agriculture, and the reduction in forested land, the relative importance of such food sources in Canadian diets has dropped.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2a/2_case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2a/2_case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the figure below, we show two major forest disturbance agents (panel a) and the results of a geospatial trend analysis (panel b to d) over a relatively small study area (26,000 ha) located along the northern boundary of Algonquin Provincial Park (Ontario). The greenness of forests, as measured by the Normalized Difference Vegetation Index (NDVI), shows trend breakpoints over an 18-year long period (2003-2020). Trend breakpoints refer to structural (abrupt) changes in the trend line of a measurement. Trend breakpoints can be positive or negative and can result from natural or anthropogenic disturbances.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ### Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1--choosing-representative-sites-and-study-areas&#34;&gt;Step 1:  Choosing representative sites and study areas&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Four study sites in the Upper Bay of Fundy along the Cumberland Basin were chosen to represent salt marshes at different stages of restoration:  Converse - newly restored, Aulac - restored over 10 years ago, John Lusby - passively restored over 50 years ago, and Wood Point Rest Stop - natural reference site. Sites were chosen to be close to one another (&lt;10 km apart) so environmental conditions like tides and weather were similar between sites. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Four sites were chosen in this study to represent salt marshes at different stages of restoration: Converse - newly restored, Aulac - restored over 10 years ago, John Lusby - passively restored over 70 years ago, and Wood Point Rest Stop - natural reference site. Sites were located close to one another (&amp;lt;10 km apart) so environmental conditions like tides and weather were similar between sites. The basemap shows the extent of tidal marsh in the Upper Bay of Fundy along the Cumberland Basin based on geospatial data available in the Canadian National Wetlands Inventory &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1b/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_1b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Each site was divided into three elevation zones that are flooded by tides differently throughout the year: the low zone is flooded by ~75% of high tides in a year, the mid zone is flooded by ~50% of high tides, and the high zone is flooded by ~25% of high tides. These zones were based on flooding frequency because decomposition of organic matter by microbes is slowed down in flooded, low-oxygen conditions. The layers displayed on the basemap for the Wood Point Rest Stop site were created by simulating different tidal flooding heights over a publicly available Digital Elevation Model (DEM) for New Brunswick &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[24]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-2--collection-of-sediment-cores&#34;&gt;Step 2:  Collection of sediment cores&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &lt;div class=&#34;images-container&#34;&gt; &#xA;![fig3](images/survey.jpg &#34; &#34;) &#xA;{width=&#34;50%&#34;}&#xA;&#xA;![fig4](images/image40.png &#34; &#34;)&#xA;{width=&#34;40%&#34;}&#xA;&#xA;![fig5](images/image17.png &#34; &#34;) &#xA;{width=&#34;40%&#34;} &#xA;&lt;/div&gt; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Three random points within each zone were chosen for core extraction using Geographic Information System (GIS) software (ArcGIS Pro) and the location of each point was surveyed using a high-accuracy GPS system. In total, nine cores were collected from each study site. The photo below (left) shows someone surveying core locations at the Aulac site. The maps below show the location of nine cores in the Wood Point Rest Stop study site within the three elevation zones. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Within a designated study area of each site, three random points within each zone were chosen for core extraction using Geographic Information System (GIS) software (ArcGIS Pro) and the location of each point was surveyed using a high-accuracy GPS system. In total, nine cores were collected from each study site. The basemap shows where the nine cores were collected in the Wood Point Rest Stop study site within the three elevation zones.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-3--processing-of-cores-in-the-lab&#34;&gt;Step 3:  Processing of cores in the lab&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once back in the lab, processing the core starts. The cores are photographed and different features like soil colour and texture are described and recorded. Then cores are divided into different increments depending on the goals of the study. For this study, 5 cm increments were chosen for a total of 10 per 50 cm core, which means that 360 individual samples were processed! When dividing cores, a compression factor should be used to adjust the increment length based on the compaction measured in the field. Compaction is often assumed equal across the entirety of the core, unless compaction is measured periodically throughout the core extraction process in the field.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-4--lab-analyses-for-bulk-density-and-loss-on-ignition-loi&#34;&gt;Step 4:  Lab analyses for bulk density and loss-on-ignition (LOI)&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--The soil samples of known volume taken from the core are first dried to determine the bulk density. Wet samples are placed in individually labeled tins, weighed, and then dried at 60 ℃ in a drying oven for 24-72 hours (or until a consistent dried weight is reached). After they are completely dry, they are re-weighed to determine dry weight of the soil sample. The photos below show the dried soil cylinders in a dessicator after the oven, which ensures the samples are fully dried before being re-weighed. Bulk density is written as the dry weight of soil divided by the known volume of the sample (grams per cm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Low bulk density means there is not a lot of soil within the volume of core sampled, which means the soil is less densely packed and there are more air pockets. Soils with low bulk density often have high organic matter content and water-holding capacity (like a sponge!). --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Wet samples are placed in individually labeled tins, weighed, and then dried at 60 ℃ in a drying oven for 24-72 hours (or until a consistent dried weight is reached). After they are completely dry, they are re-weighed to determine dry weight of the soil sample. The images below show the dried soil cylinders in a desiccator, which allows the samples to cool down to room temperature without absorbing any moisture before being re-weighed. Bulk density is written as the dry weight of soil divided by the known volume of the sample (grams per cm&lt;sup&gt;3&lt;/sup&gt;). Low bulk density means there is not a lot of soil within the volume of core sampled, which means the soil is less densely packed and there are more air pockets. Soils with low bulk density often have high organic matter content and water-holding capacity (like a sponge!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 1: Organic carbon stocks of restored salt marshes along the upper Bay of Fundy</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_1_step_5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-5--data-processing-and-interpretation&#34;&gt;Step 5:  Data processing and interpretation&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Once bulk density and % organic matter are determined, the ‘organic carbon density’ of each increment of the core can be estimated. Often % organic matter (%OM) is converted to % organic carbon (%OC) in salt marshes using a known conversion equation published in the scientific literature or roughly estimated by simply dividing %OM by 2. Some studies choose to determine the exact amount of organic carbon (%OC) in their samples by conducting ‘elemental analysis’ or sending the samples to another lab to do this analysis. More and more studies are now sending at least a subset of samples away to determine their own %OM-to-%OC conversion equations. Either way, this step involves more time to process samples or more money to pay for the analysis. In addition, soil samples should be treated to remove any inorganic carbon so elemental analysis results only reflect total organic carbon. The figure below is pulled directly from Craft et al. 1991 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt; and shows the relationship between %OM and %OC for brackish and salt marsh sediments in North Carolina. For the data presented below in this case study, a local equation for %OM-to%OC was developed using data from sites located in the Upper Bay of Fundy. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Once bulk density and % organic matter are determined, the ‘organic carbon density’ of each increment of the core can be estimated. Often % organic matter (%OM) is converted to % organic carbon (%OC) in salt marshes using a known conversion equation published in the scientific literature. Some studies choose to determine the exact amount of organic carbon (%OC) in their samples by conducting ‘elemental analysis’ and creating their own %OM-to-%OC conversion equation for their specific region. This step involves more time to process samples or more money to pay for the analysis. In addition, soil samples should be acidified to remove any inorganic carbon present so elemental analysis results only reflect total organic carbon. Maxwell et al. (2023) &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt; have recently published the most comprehensive &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41597-023-02633-x/figures/4&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;conversion equation&lt;/a&gt; for soil organic matter (SOM) to soil organic carbon (SOC) in tidal marshes to date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case study: Human pressures at different scales</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/case_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/case_study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;case-study&#34;&gt;Case study&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The human footprint is a cumulative index that quantifies the extent and the intensity of human pressures on ecosystems and biodiversity. We compared the Human footprint at three scales: global (Williams et al., 2020 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[20]&lt;/a&gt;), national (Hirsh-Pearson et al., 2022 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[21]&lt;/a&gt;), and provincial &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[22]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--The map on the right represents the state of human pressures in the northeast of British Columbia. From coarse (global) to detailed (provincial) scales, we can easily identify how roads are represented to different extents. The global model captures a broad perspective of human disturbances, in which roads and settlements are the most visible features. This global map is improved with the national model, which integrates 12 layers of information, providing the appearance of more levels of detail such as oil and gas infrastructure and mining. The provincial map, which incorporates 16 layers of information, shows a more comprehensive state of the human footprint, including seismic lines, oil and gas wells, and infrastructure, and even recreational features.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The interactive maps on the right represent the state of human pressures in the northeast of British Columbia. From coarse (Global Human Footprint) to detailed (Provincial Human Footprint) spatial resolution (scales), we can easily identify how roads are represented at different extents. The global model captures a broad perspective of human disturbances in which roads and settlements are the most visible features. The resolution of this global map is improved with the national model (National Human Footprint), which integrates 12 layers of information, providing more levels of detail such as oil and gas infrastructure and mining. The provincial map (Provincial Human Footprint), which incorporates 16 layers of information, shows a more comprehensive state of the human footprint, including seismic lines, oil and gas wells, human infrastructure, and even recreational features. By &lt;em&gt;turning on and off the different spatial layers&lt;/em&gt; on the right, differences in spatial resolution can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nature’s contributions to people: a multi-scale perspective</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/conclusion/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/conclusion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote class=&#34;blockquote text-center fst-italic fw-light&#34;&gt;&#xA;Things change as we change scales.&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Environmental processes &amp;amp; properties can shift as we change scales — whether in terms of spatial or temporal resolution and extent. For this reason, our methodological decisions can produce misleading results as we expand our research to other scales. In this story map, we illustrated some of these challenges through several case studies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Here we explore the challenges of scale in ecosystem services science and share some practical strategies to tackle them. Whether you are an undergraduate who is just starting out or a researcher diving deeper into this field, the issues and  best practices showcased here can help you navigate similar challenges in your research.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spatial and temporal scales</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/2_spatial_temporal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/2_spatial_temporal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;spatial-and-temporal-scales&#34;&gt;Spatial and temporal scales&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When we move from the bottom to the top images below, we are increasing the size of the study area (i.e., spatial extent). When we move from the left to the right images below, we are increasing the number of pixels per area (i.e., spatial resolution), which allows for individual flowers to be distinguished.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure d-block mx-auto w-75&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/Intro_C1.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Moving across images increases spatial extent or resolution. Image credit: Amanda Schwantes.&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/Intro_C1.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Moving across images increases spatial extent or resolution. Image credit: Amanda Schwantes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--- Justify middle, no text on sides --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the image below, when we move from the bottom to the top images, we are expanding the time period for which we are collecting data. When we move from the left to the right images, we are increasing the detail (e.g., number of data points per year).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A multi-scale perspective</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/3_multiscale/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/3_multiscale/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-multi-scale-perspective&#34;&gt;A multi-scale perspective&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As scientists and researchers, we often design studies at different scales, because:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;decision-makers require data at different spatio-temporal scales,&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;scientists seek to understand how ecosystem processes and properties vary across scales, and&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;there are cost and time constraints to collecting data; therefore, we target the scale most relevant for a given question or decision.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- ![fig4](images/Intro_B1.png &#34;Image credit: Amanda Schwantes&#34;) --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- {center=&#34;TRUE&#34; width=&#34;100%&#34;} --&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure mx-auto w-100&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/Intro_B1.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Image credit: Amanda Schwantes&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/Intro_B1.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Image credit: Amanda Schwantes&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--- Justify middle, no text on sides ---&gt;&#xA;&lt;!---[Add story map and scatter graphs of the scales at which we work] ---&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes data is only available (or can only be collected) at one scale; however, we may need information at a different scale to inform a decision or to understand an ecological process. We may scale up or down for many reasons, including…&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/acknowledgements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/acknowledgements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As with any field work campaign, many hands went into collecting and processing this field data. Thank you to Elisha Richardson for providing the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.behance.net/gallery/146604233/Tidal-Inundation-ArcPy-Model&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ArcPy script&lt;/a&gt; that was used to create the shapefile layers for the three flooding zones. Thank you to Emily Head, Stephanie MacIntyre, and Leila Rashid for help collecting cores in the field. Also thank you to L. Rashid for help processing bulk density and LOI samples in the lab.  Further thanks to Dr. Gail Chmura for sharing accommodations with us and Dr. Jeff Ollerhead for use of his gouge auger. Many methods used in this case study to collect and process cores were based on guidance in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thebluecarboninitiative.org/manual&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blue Carbon Manual&lt;/a&gt; by Howard et al. (2014) &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[4]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2c/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2c/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Always choose the spatial extent that makes most sense for the question you are asking&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When making predictions for a new area, check if the environmental conditions are similar to the original study area. If not, think about whether the relationship between variables might be non-linear&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Seasonal changes can also create non-linear relationships (like between temperature and time). To handle this, it might be necessary to collect data at the same time each year or more often throughout the year&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2b/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2b/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!---&#xA;1) Carefully consider the aggregation, reporting, or zonal unit by assessing variance or representativeness (i.e., percentage of outcome agreement and disagreement between scales).&#xA;2) Consider the effects of aggregating information at the ecologically meaningful level into a socially meaningful or management level. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choose a reporting unit based on the research question or management context. If these are not clear, assess and report the results from a range of scales and assess the representativeness of the assessed relationship. For example, it is recommended to quantify the percentage of outcome agreement and disagreement between scales, such as supply-demand relationship between cells and watersheds discussed in the case study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2a/3_best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2a/3_best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In cases where different data resolutions are available, the recommendation is to use data at the finest spatial resolution to ensure that potentially relevant ecological patterns are not missed. Even though fine scale data usually leads to improved accuracy (figure below, panels a &amp;amp; b), there are several constraints to keep in mind such as data availability, data storage, computing power, time, and financial resources (figure below, panel c). Finer grain size (i.e., smaller pixel size) usually leads to improved accuracy but some processes actually plateau at a certain resolution and there is no need to go finer (figure below, panel b). This threshold is often used as a baseline for future studies. Higher resolution often comes with increases in cost and time and hence, it is important to identify the most optimal resolution (grain size) for a given study based on resources available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Even when monitoring data are available for 30+ years, we know ecosystems have been changing over centuries. For example, current observations of salmon in the Salmon River are very different from historical reports &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[5]&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;figure&gt;&#xA;  &lt;blockquote class=&#34;blockquote&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;p&gt;“In the grey of early morning I … found the river full of sockeye running upstream. I put in an oar and felt that the river was half fish. The increasing light soon showed that it was red from bank to bank. Then a stampede or panic occurred, and the salmon came surging down, but the river was so full of ascending fish that they blockaded and made a great flat wriggling dam. So jammed were they that they crowded out, and were rushed up the sloping banks out of the water.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Understand the ecosystem service area&lt;/strong&gt;: Think about the whole area that benefits from the ecosystem service, like pollination, and identify who or what benefits from it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compare across beneficiaries&lt;/strong&gt;: Look at different groups or areas that benefit from the service and compare them. This can help identify different needs and how&#xA;they might be met.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Identify the benefit gap&lt;/strong&gt;: Try to figure out where the mismatches between supply and demand are. Where are the needs not being met? Understanding this gap can&#xA;help in planning how to fix it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Think about the arrangement and size of habitat areas&lt;/strong&gt;: It&amp;rsquo;s not just about how much habitat there is for the pollinators, but also about how this&#xA;habitat is arranged. The layout and size of the land can influence how well it supports the pollinators and provides the needed service.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;By considering these points, we can better understand how to manage and support many ecosystem services like pollination. It helps in creating a plan that fits&#xA;the specific needs of the area and the people who depend on these services.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This case study highlights the potential role for several best practices. These include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finding ways to combine information from multiple sources. This will be particularly important when scaling up to longer durations, when a greater variety of data sources and methods need to be used. For example, unconventional sources (e.g. historical photographs, old herbarium records) may be helpful. Bayesian methods can help assign weights to different sources, while retaining estimates of the uncertainty and flexibility in terms of the evolution of functional relationships.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Using mapping techniques, such as participatory GIS methods, to identify where current beneficiaries are in relation to the locations and services they value.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Recognizing that the future is not simply a linear extension from the past. This might mean deliberately including decision makers and beneficiaries of ecosystem services in research related to the future, through techniques such as scenarios. It might also include modelling human learning and adaptive management as part of predictions. Some researchers have recommended considering longer time extents than the focus of current decisions (e.g., Lyon et al., 2022 &lt;a href=&#34;../references/&#34;&gt;[17]&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who We Are</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/who_we_are/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/who_we_are/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-we-are&#34;&gt;Who we are&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure float-end w-25&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/resnet-logo.jpg&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/resnet-logo.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;We are part of &lt;strong&gt;NSERC ResNet&lt;/strong&gt;, a network which unites a broad community of scholars, nongovernmental organizations, government agencies, and industry sectors. We work in different regions of Canada, with a common goal of improving how we monitor, model, and manage nature’s contributions to people.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Learn more about &lt;strong&gt;NSERC ResNet&lt;/strong&gt; here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsercresnet.ca/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nsercresnet.ca/&#34;&gt;https://www.nsercresnet.ca/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure mx-auto w-100 d-block&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/resnet_map_jackie.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Landscapes where NSERC ResNet research and activities take place. Art by Jackie Hamilton&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/resnet_map_jackie.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Landscapes where NSERC ResNet research and activities take place. Art by Jackie Hamilton&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;clearfix&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;table-responsive&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;table class=&#34;align-top w-100&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;tr&gt;&#xA;&lt;td class=&#34;align-top&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;h5 id=&#34;content-authors&#34;&gt;Content Authors&lt;/h5&gt;&#xA;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;&lt;td&gt; &#xA;&lt;span class=&#34;text-muted fs-6 fw-lighter fst-italic&#34;&gt;(surname alphabetical order)&lt;/span&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Miguel Arias (Landscape 5)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;David Bysouth (Landscape 4)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;John Clark (Central Team)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Poliana Mendes (Landscape 2)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Peter Morrison (Synthesis Team)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Peter Rodriguez (Theme 3)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Brittney Roughan (Landscape 1)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Amanda Schwantes (Theme 3)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Hugo Thierry (Theme 2)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Gabriela María Torchio (Landscape 2)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Ágnes Vári (Synthesis Team)&lt;br&gt;&#xA;and Yiyi Zhang (Theme 2)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/acknowledgements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/acknowledgements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;row align-items-center&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;col&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We acknowledge the support of the Natural Sciences and Engineering Research Council of Canada (NSERC), [funding reference number NSERC NETGP 523374–18].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cette recherche a été financée par le Conseil de recherches en sciences naturelles et en génie du Canada (CRSNG), [numéro de référence NSERC NETGP 523374–18].&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;col&#34;&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&#xA;    &lt;img src=&#34;images/NSERC_RGB.png&#34; alt=&#34;NSERC logo&#34; class=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;/div&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xD;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We thank David Ferguson, Evan McNamara, and Ehsan Pashanejad for participating in ES Scaling HQP meetings and providing valuable feedback.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best practices and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best practices and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Models are very sensitive to the input data, so the more accurate the input data, the higher the reliability of the model. On the other hand, models are developed to be applied at a certain scale (spatial and temporal), and most times they are not useful to be directly applied at other scales. A model acceptable at one scale might not be at another. Another important consideration is that model evaluation can be a complex process itself. So, the larger the spatial and temporal scale of the phenomena, the evaluation of the model is more complex and challenging.&#xA;&#xA;Regarding these aspects, we suggest the following to improve reliability of model:&#xA;&#xA;1. Be clear about the purpose of the model and verify that it applies to the scale considered.  &#xA;2. Document all decisions made regarding the input data (sources, decisions made to incorporate it, etc.).  &#xA;3. Create clear and explicit criteria for every step of the model evaluation. Always document what you did and why  &#xA;4. Conduct a sensitivity analysis to test the consistency of the model under a range of input parameters.&#xA;--&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Models are very sensitive to input data, so the more accurate the input data, the higher the reliability of the model. On the other hand, models are developed to be applied at a certain scale (spatial and temporal), and most times they should not be directly applied at other scales. A model that is acceptable at one scale might not be at another. Another important consideration is that model evaluation can be a complex process in itself. Hence, the larger the spatial and temporal scale of the phenomena being studied the more complex and challenging the evaluation of the model.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Case Study 2: Soil carbon trade-offs associated with agricultural land use change in the Northwest Territories</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/case_study_2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- ### Case Study 2: Soil carbon trade-offs associated with agricultural land use change in the Northwest Territories --&gt;&#xA;&lt;h4 id=&#34;step-1-choosing-representative-sites-and-study-areas&#34;&gt;Step 1: Choosing representative sites and study areas&lt;/h4&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We partnered with communities in the Northwest Territories, Canada such as Kakisa (shown here) to understand carbon and fertility trade-offs associated with agricultural cultivation of the boreal forest.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure mx-auto d-block&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/image23.jpg&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Image by David Bysouth.&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/image23.jpg&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Image by David Bysouth.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 2019, a soil sampling effort was conducted to assess the soil fertility and carbon content of sites that communities were interested in for agricultural development. Study sites were selected across a gradient of potential agriculture suitability ranging from class 3 (potentially the most suitable for agriculture) to class 7 (likely unsuitable for agriculture). Sites were also selected based on input from local community members.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moving between scales: challenges and opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/4_moving_between/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/introduction/4_moving_between/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;moving-between-scales-challenges-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Moving between scales: challenges and opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we move between scales, which creates key challenges and opportunities. For example, the methodological choices we make at a given scale can lead to misleading results as we extend our research to other scales. In this story map, we illustrate many of these challenges and provide opportunities for overcoming them.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;div class=&#34;clearfix&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&#xA;&lt;figure class=&#34;figure single-figure mx-auto w-100&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;a href=&#34;images/Intro_D1_v2.png&#34; data-dimbox data-dimbox-caption=&#34;Image credit: Amanda Schwantes.&#34; &gt;&#xA;        &lt;img src=&#34;images/Intro_D1_v2.png&#34;&gt;&#xA;    &lt;/a&gt;&#xA;    &lt;figcaption class=&#34;figure-caption text-center&#34;&gt;Image credit: Amanda Schwantes.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&#xA;&lt;/figure&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &#xA;Learn more about:   &#xA;- [Detecting change](../challenge_2a/)  &#xA;- [Model outputs at multiple scales](../challenge_5/)  &#xA;- [Summarizing data to different units](../challenge_2b/)  &#xA;- [Collecting field data](../challenge_1/)  &#xA;- [Origin story](../challenge_4/)   &#xA;- [Consequences of generalizing results](../challenge_2c/)   &#xA;- [Mismatches](../challenge_3/)   &#xA;- [Monitoring time-period influences outcomes](../challenge_2d/) ---&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- &#xA;#### To learn more about each challenge, click on the title below:&#xA;{.text-center} --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!---[Add in finalized list of challenges: Matches what’s described in dropdown menu] ---&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_2d/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Burt DW and Wallis M. 1997. Assessment of salmonid habitat in the salmon river, salmon arm. Department of Fisheries and Oceans. Vancouver, B.C.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_3/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Torchio, G. M.; Cimon-Morin, J.; Mendes, P.; Goyette, J-O.; Schwantes, A.M.; Arias-Patino, M.; Bennett, E.M.; Destrempes, C.; Pellerin, S.  and Poulin, M. From Marginal Croplands to Natural Habitats: A Framework for Assessing the Restoration Potential to Enhance Wild-Bee Pollination in Agricultural Landscapes. Submitted for publication.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_4/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brown, G., and N. Fagerholm, 2015. Empirical PPGIS/PGIS mapping of ecosystem services: A review and evaluation, Ecosystem Services 13,119-133, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2014.10.007&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.ecoser.2014.10.007&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hillis, Dylan &amp;amp; Gustas, Robert &amp;amp; Pauly, Daniel &amp;amp; Cheung, William &amp;amp; Salomon, Anne &amp;amp; McKechnie, Iain. (2022). A palaeothermometer of ancient Indigenous fisheries reveals increases in mean temperature of the catch over five millennia. Environmental Biology of Fishes. 105. 10.1007/s10641-022-01243-7.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Krishna Bahadur KC, Arthur Gill Green, Dan Wassmansdorf, Vivek Gandhi, Khurram Nadeem, and Evan D.G. Fraser. Opportunities and trade-offs for expanding agriculture in Canada’s North: an ecosystem service perspective. FACETS. 6(): 1728-1752. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1139/facets-2020-0097&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1139/facets-2020-0097&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/refs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_5/refs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Brimicombe, A. (2010). GIS, Environmental Modeling and Engineering. CRC Press.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Hirsh-Pearson, K., Johnson, C. J., Schuster, R., Wheate, R. D., Venter, O., &amp;amp; Hirsh, K. (2022). Canada’s human footprint reveals large intact areas juxtaposed against areas under immense anthropogenic pressure. Https://Doi.Org/10.1139/Facets-2021-0063, 7, 398–419. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1139/FACETS-2021-0063&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1139/FACETS-2021-0063&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Oreskes, N., Shrader-Frechette, K., &amp;amp; Belitz, K. (1994). Verification, validation, and confirmation of numerical models in the earth sciences. Science, 263(5147), 641–646. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.263.5147.641&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1126/science.263.5147.641&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Williams, B. A., Venter, O., Allan, J. R., Atkinson, S. C., Rehbein, J. A., Ward, M., Di Marco, M., Grantham, H. S., Ervin, J., Goetz, S. J., Hansen, A. J., Jantz, P., Pillay, R., Rodríguez-Buriticá, S., Supples, C.,&#xA;Virnig, A. L. S., &amp;amp; Watson, J. E. M. (2020). Change in Terrestrial Human Footprint Drives Continued Loss of Intact Ecosystems. One Earth, 3(3), 371–382. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.009&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.oneear.2020.08.009&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Land Acknowledgements</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/land_acknowledgement/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/conclusion/land_acknowledgement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;land-acknowledgements&#34;&gt;Land Acknowledgements&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this story map we feature studies done in various regions of Canada which take place in traditional and ongoing territory of many diverse First Nations, Métis and Inuit People, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The traditional and unceded territory of the Mi’kmaq People in the Siknikt (drainage area) region of Mi&amp;rsquo;kma&amp;rsquo;ki, also known as the Upper Bay of Fundy in New Brunswick and Nova Scotia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The territory of the Ka&amp;rsquo;a&amp;rsquo;gee Tu First Nation, a Dene FIrst Nations band, located in the  Dehcho region of the Northwest Territories in the community of Kakisa&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The unsurrendered territory of the Algonquin Nations in the area known as Algonquin Provincial Park, Ontario&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The traditional territory Akwesasne and Kahnawake of the Kanien&amp;rsquo;kehá:ka in South-West Quebec&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The traditional and/or ongoing Nionwentsïo territory of the Huron-Wendat people, the Ndakina territory of the Wabanaki people, the Nitassinan territory of the Innu people and the Wolastokuk territory of the Wolastoqey people, 6. in the region known as Quebec City and its surrounding region, Quebec&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The traditional territory of Pespeselikwe te Secwépemc and Neskonlith Indian Band in the area known as the Shuswap Lake Watershed, British Columbia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;The traditional lands and territories of the Indigenous peoples who live in the province of British Columbia, particularly the unceded traditional territory of the Lheidli T’enneh First Nation, where we developed this project, home to the University of Northern British Columbia&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Best Practices and Opportunities</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/best_practices/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/best_practices/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;best-practices-and-opportunities&#34;&gt;Best Practices and Opportunities&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;!-- Collecting field data for scaling requires:&#xA;1. Funding and resources. &#xA;2. Background research to plan the most effective sampling scheme to capture as much variability as possible. &#xA;3. A network of researchers, stakeholders, and community members using standard methodologies to allow for the comparison of data across time and space. &#xA;4. Collaboration with people using the data (e.g. modelers) to help identify the type of data that will be needed before it is collected. &#xA;&#xA;Spending the time planning your field work is essential. Integration of modelers in this planning is even more important if the data is intended to be used in future studies of scaling. Planning ensures unexpected events and missing data can be dealt with and will not influence the overall dataset. --&gt;&#xA;&lt;!--Field data challenges and opportunities --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Field sampling is important for assessing many ecosystem services. However, it is important to have the following points in mind before engaging in field data collection:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>References</title>
      <link>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/references/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://docs.nsercresnet.ca/storymaps/story/scaling/challenge_1/references/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA; &lt;!--Craft, C. B., Seneca, E. D., &amp; Broome, S. W. (1991). Loss on Ignition and Kjeldahl Digestion for Estimating Organic Carbon and Total Nitrogen in Estuarine Marsh Soils: Calibration with Dry Combustion. Estuaries, 14(2), 175. https://doi.org/10.2307/1351691 --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Canadian Wildlife Services. (2023). Canadian National Wetlands Inventory [Nova Scotia and New Brunswick]. Environment and Climate Change Canada. &lt;a href=&#34;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&#34;&gt;https://data-donnees.az.ec.gc.ca/data/sites/habitat/canadian-national-wetlands-inventory&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Heiri, O., Lotter, A. F., &amp;amp; Lemcke, G. (2001). Loss on ignition as a method for estimating organic and carbonate content in sediments: Reproducibility and comparability of results. Journal of Paleolimnology, 25(1), 101–110. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008119611481&#34;&gt;https://doi.org/10.1023/A:1008119611481&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
